<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<introContent>
	<extensionContent id="org.dawnsci.intro.webresources" style="css/style.css" name="DAWN Web Resources" path="whatsnew/@">
		<group style-id="content-group" id="whatsnew-group">

<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
	&lt;b&gt;DAWN 1.4 contains many new features, below are some of the main parts.&lt;&#47;b&gt;
</text>

<text style-id="test" filteredFrom="swt">
Workflow Upgrades:
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt; 
Debug or "Stepping Mode":
Ability to ‘debug’ workflow in the UI. This means coupling the Passerelle debug 
(available with the event director model) with the Eclipse RCP debug framework. 
Using the RCP debug extensions means pydev and Passerelle debugging are linked i.e. 
break points are hit in either system during the debugging of one workflow.
 &lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt; 
Dry run ability:
This is having a more user friendly/flexible ‘mock’ system than the previous one available. 
For instance taking actors out of the loop, they grey out. Disconnecting and reconnecting 
tango motors, data collection scripts run in a test or real environment. Validation of 
spec scripts and GDA jython scripts.
 &lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
More User friendly workflow development: With better error handling. In the previous version, when developing 
a workflow you had to use the log file. Instead the user now sees an actor go red and a user 
understandable message is shown with an additional link to the right part of the log stack for experts. 
There is a tighter integration with eclipse parts – for instance the eclipse error log. This is 
linked to debug as well in that it makes it easier and more precise in feel when you develop a workflow.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>

<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
New Workflow actors
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Interactive Plot Actor: This is an actor (to be used in the ARPES pipeline but it is generic) to simplify 
the workflow and make it even easier to use. It will be a popup form similar to the review actor which shows 
a plot of the incoming data in 1D or 2D (and 3D when the plotting API is upgraded). The data may be interacted 
with tools and the resulting ROIs and other data (such as fit traces and smoothing) will be forwarded in the 
workflow message.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Pydev Actor: Similar to the current python actor, this will allow python scripts to be run in the current 
pydev configured interpreter. Breakpoints added with pydev will ideally be supported.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Tool Action actor: Ability to drive any 2D or 1D tool, for instance azimuthal integration, box profile etc. 
from the workflow using a specific actor.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>

<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
Plotting API Upgrade
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
The plotting API now allows 3D. It has been extended to 3D the elegant API design which we have
the benefit of for 1 and 2D plotting and allows new and interesting parts to be created using a 
rational API. The prototype API also fixes a number of defects in the PlotView/PlotServer interaction and 
simplifies Dawn code greatly at the point where the plot server connects to the user interface.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>

<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
Dawn Web Interface (DWI) Using RAP (Prototype made)
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
The new plotting in dawn is using draw2d which, with some modifications to existing Dawn source code, 
is available in the RAP the web interface. The DWI feature allows remote log in back to the 
visit space using fedid and password followed by the viewing of data collected. The RAP application 
supports the project explorer for the remote file space (the visit) and allows the editor parts 
used to visualise the data to run correctly (double click and open image). This has an advantage 
that in order to be viewed the data does not have to be downloaded only the current image created 
from it. In later Dawn releases, DWI could be extended to support more of the functionality of Dawn, 
tools and ipython for instance. A server (hardware) would be required to support the RAP application 
and the feature would be supported in a ‘Pre-release’ prototype format for Dawn 1.1.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>

<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
Other new features and improvements
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Toolbar Position: The plotting toolbar was long, for instance the zoom actions and the image 
tools were many. Coolbar docking has been allowed around plots meaning users can 
click and drag toolbars to the side of the plot. For instance the image tools may automatically 
appear to the side of the plot unless switched off.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Colour Scale for Intensity: This feature was discussed for Dawn 1.0. There was hope that 
the scale already existing in SWT XY-Graph would be available in time for Dawn 1.0. The 
feature is to provide a third axis apart from the positional ones correlating colour used 
with intensity value.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Masking Upgrade: This upgrade is to allow masks to be saveable and choosable from 
a list so that a user can create a mask and apply it to many images using HDF5. 
The first version will allow masks to be saved to file. Later the concept of an 
active mask may be introduced so that and image loaded of the correct size will have 
the mask applied automatically.
In addition masking has improvements for how the user interacts with the 
drawing of regions. A new method of masking has been introduced to allow single 
pixel tools to be created. The tools requires the use to zoom until no-downsampling 
is done so that individual pixels can be edited without the use of regions which are 
less precise.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Image Stack Loading: Allows the loading of a stack/directory of images as a volume, 
and displayed as such with the slicing tools.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Colour Mapping Update: Updates colour mapping tool to deal correctly with RGB images.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>
<text style-id="page-title" filteredFrom="swt">
&#8226; &lt;i&gt;
Java7 Support: A new Java7 based build of Dawn has been produced and tested in the course of Raptor.
&lt;&#47;i&gt;
</text>

       	</group>
  	</extensionContent>
</introContent>